I still ask myself if I did the right
thing, when I abandoned this floating city.
And I don't mean only for the work.
The fact is,
a friend like that,
a real friend,
you won't meet one again
if you just decide to
hang up your sea legs,
if you just want to feel
something more solid beneath your feet
and then you no longer hear
the music of the Gods around you.
But, like he used to say:
"You're never really done for
as long as you've got a good story"
"and someone to tell it to."
The trouble is, nobody would
believe a single word of my story.
It happened every time that
someone would look up and see her.
It's difficult to understand.
What I am saying is, there'd be more
than a thousand of us on that ship,
traveling rich folk,
immigrants,
and strange people and us.
Yet, there was always one,
one guy alone,
who could see her first.
Maybe he was just
sitting there eating
or walking on the deck.
Maybe he was just
fixing his pants.
And for a couple of seconds,
a quick glance out to sea
and he'd see her.
Then he'd just stand there,
rooted to the spot, his heart racing.
And every time,
every damned time, I swear,
he'd turn to us, towards the ship,
towards everybody and scream...
America!
And I lost big money betting on
who'd be the first guy to see her,
America.
- TНE LEGEND OF 1900 -
It's a miracle! Santa Rosalia!
What do you mean Santa Rosalia?
It's the Madonna of Lourdes!
New York!
The one who sees America first...
There's one on every ship.
And don't be thinking it's an accident
or some optical illusion.
It's destiny.
Those are people who always had that
precise instant stamped on their life.
And when they were kids,
you could look into their eyes
and if you looked carefully enough,
you'd already see her,
America.
And I've seen a few Americas!
Six years on that ship,
five crossings a year:
Europe, America and back.
Always soaking in the ocean!
When you stepped on land, you couldn't
even piss straight in the john.
It was steady,
the john I mean,
but you'd keep bobbing
like an idiot.
Oh, you can get off a ship all right,
but off the ocean...
I was just closing.
What can I do for you?
When I boarded
I was 24 years old,
and I only cared about one thing
in life: playing the trumpet.
I'm selling it.
A Conn.
Not bad.
Best brass money can buy!